Guide to the John Caughlan Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
- John Caughlan papers, 1933-1965; 0704-001; 22.26 cubic feet 53 boxes and one oversize folder
  - Personal and Professional Papers, 1933-1999
    - Case Files
      - Sobeleski, Helen (Grays Harbor Civil Rights Committee), 1940 (Box-folder 39/7)
      - Sulak, Frank (Immigration), 1942 (Box-folder 39/8)
      - Sutherland, Milford
        - Income Tax Matters, 1958 (Box-folder 39/9)
        - SACB Hearings, 1964 (Box-folder 39/10-40/5)
      - Swenson, H.F. vs. Seattle Central Labor Council, 1946 (Box-folder 40/6)
      - Taylor, William (Screening), 1953 (Box-folder 40/7)
      - Torres, Ponciano Mendosa (Immigration), 1950-1951, 1953 (Box-folder 40/8-11)
      - Tougaw, S.O. and Robert Olson Logging Co. (NLRB), 1947-1948 (Box-folder 40/12-13)
      - Tueter, Charles Anthony (False Statement on Application for Citizenship), 1949-1951, 1956 (Box-folder 41/1-3)
      - Van Lydegraf, Clayton (IRS), 1958 (Box-folder 41/4)
      - Ward, Alexander (U.S. Coast Guard Screening), 1952 (Box-folder 41/5)
      - Warner, Tom adv. City of Seattle, 1962 (Box-folder 41/6)
      - Washington Pension Union
        - Correspondence
        - Chronological, 1940-1942, 1945-1949 (Box-folder 41/7-41/8)
        - Dill, Clarence C. (re Initiative 141), 1940 (Box-folder 41/9)
        - Cases
          - Canwell Hearings, 1941-1942, 1946-1949 (Box-folder 41/10)
          - WPU vs. State of Washington rel. Dana T. Robinson (Canwell), 1948 (Box-folder 41/11-12)
        - Individual Cases
          - State of Washington in re Edward Pettus vs. Olzendam, dir. Dept. of Social Security, 1949-1951 (Box-folder 41/13-14)
          - WPU & William J. Pennock, et al. vs. Olzendam, R. – Dir. Dept. of Soc. Security (WA) re Init. 178, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 41/15-16)
          - WPUb vs. Cliff Yelle, Auditor, State of WA, 1948 (Box-folder 41/17)
          - Proposed (Subversive) Designation of the American Bar Association by the Attorney General, 1953 (Box-folder 41/18)
          - Brownell vs. W.P.U., 1954 (Box-folder 41/19)
          - WPU vs. Subversive Activities Control Board, 1962-1965 (Box-folder 41/20)
          - Anderson, Morris et al. vs. Olzendam, R. – Dir. Dept. of Social Security (WA), 1950 (Box-folder 42/1)
          - Calkins, Duff, Kolloen, 1941, 1947, 1948 (Box-folder 42/2)
          - Carpenter, Emma R., 1951 (Box-folder 42/3)
          - Giles, Harry, 1949 (Box-folder 42/4)
          - Judd, Emma (Old Age Assistance Grant), 1953 (Box-folder 42/5)
          - Kroener, Edmond G., 1949 (Box-folder 42/6)
          - Larson, Ada Maud, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 42/7)
          - Pennock, William vs. Townsend National Weekly (Libel), 1952, 1953 (Box-folder 42/8)
          - Regnier, David H, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 42/9)
          - Robinson, Ira V. and Libby H., 1945-1951, 1954 (Box-folder 42/10-11)
        - WPU 16th Annual Convention, 1953 (Box-folder 42/12)
        - Newsletter, 1953 (Box-folder 42/13)
        - Notes, undated (Box-folder 42/14)
        - Miscellany (Box-folder 42/15)
        - Clippings, undated (Box-folder 42/16)
      - Wheeler, Don (Subpoena), 1953 (Box-folder 42/17)
      - Wilkins, Eugene M. vs. Carlander, C., et al., Commissioners, Port of Seattle (Non Subversive Oath), 1956-1957 (Box-folder 42/18)
      - Wolf, Hazel A. (Immigration)
        - Biographical Features, undated (Box-folder 42/19)
        - General Correspondence, 1947-1962, undated (Box-folder 42/20-43/7)
        - Pleadings, 1947-1961, undated (Box-folder 43/8-45/10)
        - Transcripts, 1949-1950, 1957, 1961 (Box-folder 45/11-46/4)
        - Senate Bill No. 1425, 1954, 1956 (Box-folder 46/5-6)
        - Notes, 1949-1961, undated (Box-folder 46/7-10)
        - Photograph, undated (Box-folder 46/11)
        - Legal Documents – Photostats, 1958 (Box-folder 46/12)
        - Clippings, 1947-1957 (Box-folder 46/13)
        - Miscellany, 1961 (Box-folder 46/14)
      - Wolf, Walter (Immigration), 1954-1955 (Box-folder 46/15)
      - Canwell Hearings and Resulting Cases
        - General Correspondence, 1948-1950 (Box-folder 47/1)
        - Clients
          - Butterworth, Joseph vs. Edward H. Lauer (UW), 1948 (Box-folder 47/2)
          - Forschmiedt, Rachmiel adv. State of WA, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 47/3-5)
            See also: Huff, et al.
          - Gundlach, Ralph adv. State of WA, 1949
            - Transcript – Statement of Facts Vols. I and II (Box-folder 47/6-7)
            - Pleadings – Appeal, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 48/1-3)
            - Notes, 1950 (Box-folder 48/4)
          - James, Burton, 1948-1950, undated (Box-folder 48/5-8)
          - James, Florence Bean
            - Pleadings
              - King County Superior Court, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 48/9-13)
              - Washington Supreme Court, 1949 (Box-folder 48/14-15)
              - U.S. Supreme Court, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 48/16)
            - Speeches and Writings, undated (Box-folder 48/17)
            - Lists – Seattle Repertory Playhouse (Box-folder 48/18)
          - Ottenheimer, Albert, 1948-1951 (Box-folder 48/19-21)
          - Pennock, William J., 1948 (Box-folder 48/22)
          - Phillips, Herbert J., 1948 (Box-folder 49/1-2)
          - The Seattle Six:
            The Seattle Six are Forschmiedt, Ralph Gundlach, Florence James, Burton James, Albert. Ottenheimer, and Herbert Phillips.
            - General Correspondence, 1951 (Box-folder 49/3)
            - Pleadings, undated (Box-folder 49/4-6)
            - Financial Records (Box-folder 49/7)
            - Briefing Material, 1948 (Box-folder 49/8)
            - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 49/9)
          - Washington Pension Union, 1948 (Box-folder 49/10-11)
        - Witnesses
          - Armstrong, H. C., 1948 (Box-folder 49/12)
          - Budenz, Louis, 1948 (Box-folder 49/13)
          - Costigan, Howard and Isabel, 1948 (Box-folder 49/14)
          - Eldridge, Sarah M., 1948 (Box-folder 49/15)
          - Fogg, Kathryn, 1948 (Box-folder 49/16)
          - Hewitt, George (aka Holmes), 1948 (Box-folder 49/17)
          - Honig, Nat and Mrs. I., undated (Box-folder 49/18)
          - Huson, Homer, 1938, 46, 48, 54 (Box-folder 49/19-20)
          - Jewell, Moro (Detective), 1948 (Box-folder 49/21)
          - Kirk, Chris Elmer, undated (Box-folder 50/1)
          - Re: Leech, John, 1950 (Box-folder 50/2)
          - Smith, Claude M. and R., undated (Box-folder 50/3)
          - Smith, Howard F., 1948 (Box-folder 50/4)
          - Sunoo, Harold, 1959, 1953 (Box-folder 50/5)
          - Warren, Ward Firman, undated (Box-folder 50/6)
        - Subject Files
          - Government Witnesses, 1948 (Box-folder 50/7)
          - Canwell Hearing Witnesses, undated (Box-folder 50/8)
        - Miscellany, 1948 (Box-folder 50/9)
        - Vouchers, 1947, 1948 (Box-folder 50/10)
    - General Correspondence, 1945-1949, undated (Box-folder 50/11-13)
      - Cain, Harry – Resignation, 1956 (Box-folder 50/14)
      - Civil Rights, 1953, 1956 (Box-folder 50/15)
      - Harbor Probe, Seattle, 1953 (Box-folder 50/16)
      - Immigration and Deportation Materials, 1947-1953 (Box-folder 50/17-51/3)
        Includes item related to Coast Guard Screening.
      - International Workers Order, 1954 (Box-folder 51/4)
      - U.S. House of Representatives, Committee on Un-American Activities (Velde Committee), 1954 (Box-folder 51/5-6)
    - Jury Lists, Data (Box-folder 51/7)
    - Notes, 1954 (Box-folder 51/8)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 51/9)
    - Ephemera
      - Civil Rights Congress [Newsletters]
        - Civil Rights Law Letter, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 51/10)
        - International Association of Democratic Lawyers, 1957, 1962 (Box-folder 51/11)
        - International Institute for Peace, 1962, 1963 (Box-folder 51/12)
      - The Reporter, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 51/13)
      - World Council for Peace, Bulletin of the, 1962-1965 (Box-folder 51/14)
      - Pamphlets (miscellaneous) (Box-folder 51/15)
    - Clippings
      - Communist Trials, 1952 (Box-folder 52/1)
      - Caughlan Contempt of Court, 1950, 1952 (Box-folder 52/1)
      - “Reds” Trials, 1955 (Box-folder 52/2)
      - UW Professors Charged with Communist Activities, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 52/3)
    - Case Files – Others, 1935 (Box-folder 52/4)
      Includes three immigration cases that were not related to Caughlan.
    - Miscellany, 1948-1949, undated (Box-folder 52/5)
  - Related Organizations' Records, 1950-1998
    - ACLU Washington, Due Process Committee, 1965 (Box-folder 52/6)
    - American Committee for the Protection of the Foreign Born
      - General Correspondence, 1948-1950, 1964 (Box-folder 52/7)
      - U.S Supreme Court Cases, 1952, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 52/8)
      - Newsletter - Bulletin: ACPBF, 1953-1959, 1967 (Box-folder 52/9-10)
      - Miscellany, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 52/11)
    - Committee to Secure Justice for Martin Sobell, 1956, 1959-1960, 1964 (Box-folder 53/1)
    - Pennock (William J.) Memorial Association, 1953-1955, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 53/2-3)
    - Progressive Party of Washington Nominating Convention, 1948 (Box-folder 53/4)
    - Washington Social Security Committee, 1940-1952 (Box-folder 53/5-8)
- John Caughlan papers, 1936-1999; 1950-1989; 0704-002; 32.39 cubic feet 32 boxes, two oversize folders and two vertical files
  Personal and Professional Papers, 1936-1999
  This accession consists largely of case files (which include correspondence, pleadings, reports, newsletters and related material) and documents Caughlan's cases from the 1940s through1990s; significant cases include United States vs. Robel, Schneider vs. Smith, Domingo et al. vs. Ferdinand Marcos et al., conscientious objector cases, and cases involving members of the Black Panthers, including Elmer Dixon. Also included is addition material related to Caughlan's work on behalf of clients called to testify in the Canwell Committee hearings. Subject files document his interest in and visits to Mexico, Central America, and the Philippines. Caughlan's partial autobiography is in the Writings file; other of his writings are interspersed in the papers (their presence has been marked with a note whenever possible). Related organizations' records show his involvement with the National Lawyers Guild, both on the national and local levels; material types include correspondence, agendas and minutes, working notes, conference and convention files, and historical materials. A photo album of the Seattle chapter's 50th anniversary is also present. A copy of Caughlan's FBI file is also included.
  Open to all users, but access to portions of the papers restricted. Contact repository for details.
  Gift of Goldie Caughlan, August 19, 1999.
  - Personal and Professional Papers, 1936-1999
    - Biographical Features
      - 80th Birthday Celebration, 1989 (Box-folder 1/1)
        John Caughlan's 80th birthday celebration was a "roast" which also served as a fundraiser for the Committee for Justice for Domingo and Viernes; this file includes the printed program from the event as well as copies of some of the tributes presented.
      - Memorial, May 29, 1999 (Box-folder 1/2-3)
        Includes memorial program as well as tributes written for the occasion by friends and associates, and the materials from a display of Caughlan's Supreme Court cases.
      - Vital Records, 1964, 1976 (Box-folder 1/4)
      - Clippings, 1987, 1999 (Box-folder 1/5)
        Includes Seattle Times obituary and Bar Bulletin article about Caughlan's career.
    - Speeches and Writings
      - Autobiography draft, undated (Box-folder 1/6-7)
      - Article on McCarran Act in American Civil Liberties Union News, 1964 (Box-folder 1/8)
      - Miscellaneous, 1980, 1982, undated (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation File
      - Part 1, 1941-1946 (Box-folder 1/10-11)
      - Part 2, 1946-1950 (Box-folder 1/12-13)
      - Part 3, 1951-1963 (Box-folder 1/14-16)
      - Part 4, 1963-1972 (Box-folder 1/17-18)
      - Miscellany, 1947-1979 (Box-folder 1/19-24)
        Includes one unidentified, undated snapshot, presumably of Caughlan's family.
    - Case Files
      - Allen, Eugenia (Expulsion from Office Employees' International Union, Local 8), undated (Box-folder 1/25)
      - Bennett, Clarence (Police Misconduct, False Arrest), 1973 (Box-folder 1/26)
      - Bouiss, Helene (Immigration), 1946 (Box-folder 1/27)
      - Braune, Paul (Disbarment), 1961-1962 (Box-folder 1/28)
      - Brooks, C.J. and Reddit, Robert (Contempt of Court and False Statements in case of Ermie Estill), 1956-1957 (Box-folder 1/29)
      - Brown, Janette (Nuclear Train; Peace Law; Protest Defense), 1985 (Box-folder 1/30-31)
      - Browning, Ola M. and John P. (vs. Slenderella; Discrimination), 1959 (Box-folder 1/32)
      - Brunnenkant, Siegfried
        - Security Clearance Hearing
          - Incoming Letters, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 1/33)
          - Outgoing Letters, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 1/34)
          - Pleadings, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 1/35-36)
          - Transcript, 1970 (Box-folder 2/1-2)
          - Notes, 1966-1970, undated (Box-folder 2/3)
        - vs. Melvin Laird, Secretary of Defense (Security Clearance Appeal)
          - Incoming Letters, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 2/4)
          - Outgoing Letters, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 2/5)
          - Pleadings, 1973, undated (Box-folder 2/6-7)
          - Exhibits, undated (Box-folder 2/8-10)
      - Bullock, Ethel (Loyalty), 1948-1952, undated (Box-folder 2/11)
      - Butler, Benjamin (Loitering, Constitutionality), 1947, undated (Box-folder 2/12)
      - Byrd, Abraham Ruddell (Rudy) (Conscientious Objector, Court Martial)
        - Incoming Letters, 1969, 1972 (Box-folder 2/13)
        - Outgoing Letters, 1969, undated (Box-folder 2/14)
        - Pleadings, 1969 (Box-folder 2/15)
        - Record of Trial, Summarized, 1968 (Box-folder 2/16)
        - Record of Trial, Verbatim, 1969 (Box-folder 2/17-18)
        - Notes, 1968-1969, undated (Box-folder 2/19)
      - Cannery Workers' and Farm Workers' Union, Local 7 (Attempted Dissolution of Local by King County), undated (Box-folder 2/20)
      - Canwell Hearings
        - Historical Features, 1997-1998, undated (Box-folder 2/21)
        - General Correspondence, 1947 (Box-folder 2/22)
        - Incoming Letters, 1948-1957 (Box-folder 2/23)
        - Outgoing Letters, 1952, 1957, 1980 (Box-folder 2/24)
        - Resolutions, 1947 (Box-folder 2/25)
        - Pleadings
          - Butterworth, Joseph (Edward H. Lauer vs. Butterworth), 1948 (Box-folder 2/26-3/7)
          - Friel, Brother Edward, 1947 (Box-folder 3/8-11)
          - Gundlach, Ralph, undated
            - Gundlach vs. Norman R. Riddell, undated (Box-folder 3/12)
            - State of Washington vs. Gundlach, undated (Box-folder 3/13)
          - James, Florence Bean (State of Washington vs. Bean), undated (Box-folder 3/14-16)
          - Phillips, Herbert J.
            - Edward Lauer vs. Phillips, 1949 (Box-folder 3/17-18)
            - Phillips vs. United States, 1953, undated (Box-folder 3/19-20)
        - Subject File: All Powers Project, 1997-1998, undated (Box-folder 3/21)
          All Powers Necessary and Convenient was a play presented at the University of Washington about the Canwell hearings and the dismissal of several University faculty members.
        - Clippings, 1948-1950, undated (Box-folder 3/22)
        - Ephemera, undated (Box-folder 3/23)
        - Photographs and negatives, circa 1947-1948 (Box-folder 32/20-23)
      - Cassidy, Douglas (Conscientious Objector)
        - General Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 3/24)
        - Selective Service Paperwork, 1967-1968, undated (Box-folder 3/25-26)
        - Notes, undated (Box-folder 3/27)
      - Caughlan, John
        - United States vs. Caughlan (Perjury)
          - Transcript, 1948 (Box-folder 3/28-29)
          - Clippings, 1948 (Box-folder 3/30)
          - Ephemera, undated (Box-folder 3/31)
        - Washington State vs. Caughlan, 1951 (Box-folder 3/32)
        - vs. International Longshoremen's Union, Local 37-C (Recovery of Fees), 1957-1958 (Box-folder 3/33)
        - vs. Seattle Post-Intelligencer (Libel), 1965 (Box-folder 3/34)
        - Washington State Bar Association vs. Caughlan, 1968, undated (Box-folder 3/35)
        - Contempt of Court (Larry Ward Inquest), 1970 (Box-folder 3/36)
        - Estate of Hendrik Barslaag vs. Caughlan, 1976, undated (Box-folder 3/37)
        - Gwendolyn Williams Grievance Regarding Estate of James Williams, 1994 (Box-folder 3/38)
      - Clemente, Serna (Immigration), 1953 (Box-folder 4/1)
      - Collins, Bishop (Right to Counsel), 1968-1969, undated (Box-folder 4/2)
      - Corley, Milton (vs. National Maritime Union; Refusal to Register, Loyalty), 1957-1958 (Box-folder 4/3)
      - Crabshell Alliance (Washington Public Power Supply System vs.) (Trespassing; Peace Law; Nuclear Defense)
        Additional material relating to this case can be found in the National Lawyers Guild material in the Related Organizations' Records section of this accession.
        - General Correspondence of Legal Team, 1978-1979, undated (Box-folder 4/4)
        - Minutes of Legal Team Meetings, 1978-1979, undated (Box-folder 4/5)
        - Pleadings, 1978, undated (Box-folder 4/6-7)
        - Notes and Research, 1978, undated (Box-folder 4/8-9)
      - Crain, James Joseph (Immigration), undated (Box-folder 4/10)
      - Craycroft, Peter (Conscientious Objector; Court Martial)
        - Incoming Letters, 1967-1978 (Box-folder 4/11)
        - Outgoing Letters, 1967-1978 (Box-folder 4/12)
        - Record of Trial, Summarized, 1967 (Box-folder 4/13)
        - Record of Trial, Verbatim, 1968 (Box-folder 4/14)
        - Pleadings
          - vs. Clark Clifford et al.
            - United States District Court, 1968, undated (Box-folder 4/15)
            - United States Court of Appeals, 1968 (Box-folder 4/16)
          - vs. Ferrall et al.
            - United States District Court, 1968 (Box-folder 4/17)
            - United States Court of Appeals, 1968 (Box-folder 4/18)
          - Combined Cases
            - United States District Court, 1973 (Box-folder 4/19)
            - United States Court of Appeals, 1968, 1970 (Box-folder 4/20)
            - United States Supreme Court, 1969 (Box-folder 4/21)
        - Notes, undated (Box-folder 4/22)
        - Reference Cases, 1966, undated (Box-folder 4/23)
        - "Miscellany", 1967-1968, undated (Box-folder 4/24)
      - Cuadra, Santos vs. Queen Fisheries
        - Discrimination, 1955 (Box-folder 4/25)
        - Injury, 1955 (Box-folder 4/26)
      - Dailey, Cecil E. (vs. Seattle Housing Authority; Constitutionality of Gwinn Amendment), undated (Box-folder 4/27)
      - Dickens, Calloway Ronald (Robbery): Pleadings, 1965 (Box-folder 4/28)
      - Dixon, Aaron (State of Washington vs. Dixon; Unlawful Assembly; Black Panthers), circa 1969 (Box-folder 4/29)
      - Dixon, Elmer (Black Panther)
        - State of Oregon vs. Dixon (Armed Robbery)
          - Incoming Letters, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 4/30)
          - Outgoing Letters, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 4/31)
          - Transcript of Trial, United States District Court, 1969 (Box-folder 4/32-5/4)
          - Pleadings
            - Oregon State Court of Appeals, 1970-1971, undated (Box-folder 5/5-6)
            - United States Supreme Court, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 5/7)
          - Notes, undated (Box-folder 5/8)
        - Custody of Merrill Dixon, 1974, undated (Box-folder 5/9)
        - Dixon et al. vs. Washington Natural Gas Company, et al. (Illegal Surveillance; Wiretapping)
          - General Correspondence, 1974 (Box-folder 5/10)
          - Pleadings, undated (Box-folder 5/11)
          - Notes and Research, 1969, undated (Box-folder 5/12)
          - Clippings, 1970, 1973, undated (Box-folder 5/13)
        - Investigation of Seattle Black Panther Party; Congressional Hearing, 1970 (Box-folder 5/14)
      - Domingo, Silme and Gene Viernes
        - Domingo et al. vs. Republic of the Philippines, Ferdinand Marcos et al.
          - Timeline and Background, undated (Box-folder 5/15)
          - Incoming Letters, 1981-1989 (Box-folder 5/16)
          - Outgoing Letters, 1981-1993 (Box-folder 5/17)
          - Memoranda of Legal Team, 1987-1991
            - Regarding Marcos' Secret Intelligence Slush Fund, undated (Box-folder 5/18)
            - From Ring Binder, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 5/19-23)
            - Chronological, 1981-1991 (Box-folder 5/24-29)
          - Pleadings
            - List of Docket Entries, 1990 (Box-folder 5/30)
            - Volume I, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 6/1-3)
            - Volume II, 1983, undated (Box-folder 6/4-5)
            - Volume III, 1983-1984, undated (Box-folder 6/6-7)
            - Volume IV, 1985-1986, undated (Box-folder 6/8-9)
            - Volume V, 1983 (Box-folder 6/10)
            - Volume VI, 1985, undated (Box-folder 6/11-12)
            - Volume VII, 1984 (Box-folder 6/13-14)
            - Volume VIII, 1982-1987 (Box-folder 6/15-16)
            - Volume IX, 1983-1985, undated (Box-folder 6/17-18)
            - Volume X, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 6/19)
            - Chronological
              A transcript of Ferdinand Marcos' videotaped deposition is in the folders for 1986.
              - 1982-1984 (Box-folder 6/20-26)
              - 1985-1987 (Box 7)
              - 1988-1989 (Box 8)
              - 1990-1993 (Box-folder 9/1-2)
            - Drafts and Fragments, undated (Box-folder 9/3-4)
          - Miscellany, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 9/5-7)
            Includes pleadings; contents are in original order.
          - Exhibits, undated (Box-folder 9/8-9)
          - Daily Trial Summaries, 1989 (Box-folder 9/10)
          - Transcript (Volume II), 1988-1989 (Box-folder 9/11-12)
          - Deposition Summaries, 1983-1988 (Box-folder 9/13-14)
          - Testimony in Criminal Trial of Jimmy Ramil and Pompeyo (Ben) Guloy
            - Annotated Summary, undated (Box-folder 9/15)
            - Partial Summary, undated (Box-folder 9/16)
            - Verbatim Transcript, Robert San Pablo, 1982 (Box-folder 9/17)
          - Financial Records, 1983, 1992, undated (Box-folder 9/18-20)
            Includes fee agreements, summaries of charges, and memoranda regarding distribution of settlement monies.
          - Committee for Justice for Domingo and Viernes, 1981-1989, undated (Box-folder 9/21-22)
            Includes administrative records, ephemera, and copies of Call for Justice, the Committee's national newsletter, and Update, the newsletter of the Committee's Seattle branch.
          - Background Material on Philippines, 1968, 1977-1978, 1981, 1999 (Box-folder 9/23-30)
            Includes writings by Caughlan, including a report on his 1977 trip to the Philippines. Also present are negatives and contact sheet of photographs from his 1977 trip, as well as publications, ephemera, articles and notes relating to labor issues, human rights abuses, and the World Peace Through Law conference that was held in Manila in 1977. Correspondents include Friends of the Filipino People.
          - Notes and Research Material, undated (Box-folder 10/1-9)
          - Collateral Case: Pleadings in Domingo et al. vs. Leonilo Malabed, 1991, undated (Box-folder 10/10-15)
          - Clippings, 1981-1989, undated (Box-folder 10/16-18)
          - Ephemera, 1981-1982, undated (Box-folder 10/19)
            Includes programs of memorials for Domingo and Viernes.
        - Terri J. Mast [Executrix of Domingo's Estate] vs. Hartford Accident and Indemnity Company and Keerkor Bedayan
          Bonita Clarke notes that this does relate to the case against Marcos, "even though it seems only an insurance matter."
          - Incoming Letters, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 10/20)
          - Outgoing Letters, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 10/21)